[Music]
Hello and thank you for watching. If
you're using Shify Plus, you have
multiple benefits. One of it is more
powerful and flexible way to define
customer in Shopify terminology company.
You can specify payment terms. You can
define multiple buyers who will be
performing transactions. And you can
define specific prices for it and
multiple locations and uh each location
actually can represent a different
business uh legal entity. And here is a
catch because in business central
uh each legal entity is a customer.
Let's see how we can combine these
together. In my online store in the
Shopify currently I have only one B2B
customer. I'm just starting. And you can
see it has a HQ office, but it also has
three locations, east and west in
addition to HQ. And you can see that it
uses different payment terms and it has
a different addresses. Let's take a look
at this one for example. It has address
which says west. And I created uh three
orders for each of these locations.
Let's try and import them into Business
Central. Let's navigate to list of
orders
and import orders from Shopify.
All right, you can see that all three
orders were imported and all of them are
assigned to the same customer. Uh I
decided to use the code to represent
like Adventure Works. All right, let's
review the list of companies.
Actually list of companies contains only
one company because this is the number
of companies we had in the Shopify and
you can see that it was automatically
mapped to customer number. How? By tax
ID. But uh you can see also there is a
number of locations in this fact box.
Can we navigate the full list? Yes, we
have a button which is called Shopify
locations which opens the list of
locations. And if you scroll to the
right, you can see the different
addresses,
different tax information, different
payment terms, and two new fields. Sell
to customer and it should be bill to
customer number.
And this one you can use for more
advanced mapping scenarios. Let's do
following. For the first one, which is
HQ, we are going to keep it empty. But
for east and west we will do some
changes. So for east we will define uh
adventure work east the separate
customer and for west you already
guessed it will be west but we also can
specify a different build to customer.
It will be adventure works invoicing.
All right. And uh now let's go to the
list of orders.
I deleted them so far. And now let's
synchronize them again. Sync orders from
Shopify.
You can see there are again same orders
I imported but this time sell to
customer is different. It's not only HQ
but it's now used west and east. And if
we open the order created for west
customer, sell customer and scroll down,
you can see that build to customer is
also different like the one which we
defined in the Shopify location mapping.
And if you create sale document,
you can see the sales order created for
HQ has sell to and build to customers
the same, but for West they are
different.
All right. You may ask like what if in
your business processes customer first
created in the business central and you
have like several customers and now you
need to create Shopify company with
multiple locations. Let's explore. First
of all, let's take a look at the list of
customers and I created view to include
only Fabricom customers. the same
pattern. We have one HQ company and we
have north and south and for south
Fabricom in is defined as a bill to
customer. Let's check. Scroll down.
Exactly. Invoicing
Fabricom in uh invoicing is used as a as
a billing customer. All right. Now in
Shopify connector, let's open list of
companies and start by adding a new
company.
We are adding Fabricam HQ headquarters.
All right, done
with one address. Now we navigate to the
list of locations and then we can choose
add customers as Shopify locations.
Okay,
two more locations were added for each
company which you selected. And if you
scroll to the right, we can see they
have a different tax registration
addresses, payment terms where I defined
them. Apparently, I didn't define it for
South. But moreover, in sell to and bill
to customers, you can see that values
are populated. Now, when order will be
imported from Shopify into Business
Central, the correct sell to customer
will be assigned automatically. Let's
take a look at the Shopify admin now. uh
list of the companies in Shopify. You
can see that Fabricam HQ was added and
it has three locations HQ north and
south. And uh moreover, if we explore
here, we can see that uh we got uh
employees created. But you can also see
the something which says mixed catalog
and mixed payment terms because now we
are in the company level. But if you go
to the location level,
you can see that uh
we have a different catalog
fabric, fabric north and fabric south.
So all of this uh depends on the setting
in the business central if you want to
create catalogs automatically or not.
All right. Now you can see how to deal
with different locations especially if
they representing different legal
entities and either if they created in
Shopify and then imported into business
central or if they are created in
business central and how you can push
them to the shipy. Thank you for
watching. Check additional information
in descriptions and uh bye.